Guide to the Ronald Shiffman collection on the Pratt Center for Community Development 2013.023
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 1: Community Planning Projects
  - Rebuild Chinatown Initiative, 2001-2002 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Rebuilding New York City, 2001-2002 (Box 17, Folder 10-12)
  - Rebuilding New York City, 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Red Hook, 1992-1996 (Box 18, Folder 3-5)
  - Red Hook 197a, 1993-1995 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
  - Red Hook Zoning Summary, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Red Hook: A Plan for Community Regeneration, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Regional Plan Association, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Regional Plan Association Brooklyn Waterfront Grenway Plan, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Riverside South, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Ron Shiffman, Red Hook Master, undated (Box 142, Item 428)
  - Selections from the Greenpoint Video Project -- The 1999 Waterfront Conference; Adam Brown, Working Waterfront Association; The Waterfront Museum, Red Hook; The Restoration of Newtown Creek; Greenpoint's Waterfront Access; Pier 63—a July 4th Canceled; The Floating Pool, 2001 (Box 142, Item 446)
  - Selections from the Greenpoint Video Project -- Waterfront Conference, Waterfront Museum, Greenpoint's Waterfront Access, Pier 63—A July 4th Canceled, The Floating Pool, Brownfields Conference, 1st Day Closing Remarks and City Hall Reception, undated (Box 142, Item 445)
  - Selections from the Greenpoint Video Projects -- O.U.T.R.A.G.E. and The Watchperson Project, undated (Box 142, Item 444)
    VHS. Runtime: 0:45:00
  - South Bronx, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Sports Stadium Brooklyn Sports Complex Development Study, 1986-1988 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - St Nicks Planning Technical Assistance Saint Nicholas Neighborhood Preservation Corporation, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Staten Island Photographs, 1980-2017 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Strategic Plan for Brooklyn Empowerment Zone, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Student Studies, Various -- Sunset Park, Wyandanch NY, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
  - Survey of Bronx Organizations -- Ford Foundation, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Testimony May 3, 2001, 2000-2001 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - The Downtown Association, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - The Parks Council, 1989-1992 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Town Planning Post Auschwitz -- Personal Reflections, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Two Trees Proposal -- Downtown Brooklyn Waterfront, Interbridge Area, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - United Jewish Organizations Miscellaneous, 1998-2000 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Williamsburg 197a Waterfront Plan, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Williamsburg 197a Waterfront Plan, 1998-2000 (Box 110, Folder 2-4)
  - Williamsburg Bridge Area Rezoning, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Williamsburg Waterfront 197a Plan, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Series 2: Housing Programs and Policy
  A wide variety of housing programs and policies are documented in this series, including mutual housing and land trusts, as well as artist housing, Single Room Occupancies (SROs), low-income home ownership and rehabilitation programs, rent regulation, and housing preservation. The majority of materials are from the early 1980s through 2010. The first sub-series includes general files on a large scope of policies and programs pertaining primarily to New York City. These topics are documented in meeting minutes, proposals, clippings, testimony, reports and correspondence.
  The second sub-series includes material pertaining to specific mutual housing and land trust projects in New York City. These include Strycker's Bay, Cooper Square, Midwood Friends, the Mutual Housing Association, and the United Tenants Association.
  Materials in this series are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Sub-series 2.1: General
    - 14th Regiment Armory, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - 25th Anniversary Conference November -- Lunch Plenary, 1990 (Box 140, Item 356)
      Audiocasette. Runtime: 1:40:00
    - 25th Anniversary Conference November -- Lunch Plenary, 1990 (Box 140, Item 355)
    - 25th Anniversary Conference -- Strengthening the Community, 1990 (Box 140, Item 357)
    - 25th Anniversary Conference -- Session 1, 1990 (Box 140, Item 354)
      Audiocasette. Runtime: 1:30:00
    - 25th Anniversary Conference -- Human Resource Development, 1990 (Box 140, Item 353)
    - 25th Anniversary Conference -- Housing Center, 1990 (Box 140, Item 352)
    - 25th Anniversary Conference -- Generating Wealth Center, 1990 (Box 140, Item 351)
    - 25th Anniversary Conference -- Economic Development Center, 1990 (Box 140, Item 350)
    - 25th Anniversary Conference -- Alleviating Poverty Center, 1990 (Box 140, Item 349)
    - 25th Anniversary Conference -- Alleviating Poverty Center, 1990 (Box 140, Item 348)
    - 2077 -- Division of Housing and Community Renewal, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - 2109 -- Division of Housing and Community Renewal, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - A Labour Managed Social Investment Fund, Ontario, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Advanced Housing Degiovanni/Allen, September 30, 1985 (Box 138, Item 298)
      VHS. Runtime: 0:30:16
    - Affordable Housing Clippings, 1987-1989 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Affordable Housing Incentives Program, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Affordable Housing, Ossining, NY, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - An Analysis of the Politics of Urban Renewal, 1962-1975 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Analysis of the DHCR Proposal for a Welfare Housing Demonstration Program, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Appointments from Mayor, 1990-1993 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Artists' Housing, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Baptist Women's Residence -- Single-Room Occupancy, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Big Apple Coalition for Housing, 1984-1985 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Brooklyn Museum Neighborhood Study, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Campaign Finance Reform Bill Letter, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - CC-HR Housing Opportunities for Families with Children, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Chase Manhattan Corporation Housing and Economic Development Grant, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Citizen Advisory Committee Meetings -- Information, 1979-1982 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Citizen Participation in REM Workshop, April 13, 1978 (Box 141, Item 337)
    - Citizen's Committee for NYC, 1981-1983 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Citizen's HSG and Planning Council, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - City Hall Hearings and Advocacy Meetings, 2002-2003 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Coalition Against Redlining, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Columbia University Colloquium on Housing, 1980-1989 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Commercial Rent Control in New York City Proposed 1985 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Committee to Rebuild New York - Richard Kahan's Run for Governorship, 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Community-Government Collaboration, 1995-2014 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Congress for New Urbanism -- Jonathan Rose and Co., 1999-2001 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Congress of the United States, 1981-1998 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Consumer-Farmer Foundation, 1982-1993 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Consumer-Farmer Foundation, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Contract with America, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Crown Heights Federal Code Enforcement Program, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Cuomo, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Density -- P. Marcuse, 1981-1994 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Development Commitments Study Commission, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Disposition of City Owned Property, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Disposition of City Owned Property -- Active, 1990-1991 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Division of Housing and Community Renewal, 1980-1989 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Division of Housing and Community Renewal -- Low Income Turnkey Enhanced Housing Trust Fund, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Eastern Region Neighborhood Government Meeting, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Faith Based Housing Development, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation -- Leadership in Affecting Policy, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Ford Foundation -- South Africa Community Reinvestment, 1991-1992 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      Contains one 5 1/2" Floppy Disk
    - Foundation for the Support of Neighborhood-Based Development, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - "Hardship in the Heartland" Housing for the Homeless Report, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Harold DeRienzo's Presentation -- Columbia University, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Harvard University -- Innovations in State and Local Government, undated (Box 138, Item 307)
    - Home Improvement Program (HIP), 1982-1984 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Home Ownership Opportunities, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Housing, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Housing -- Robert Shur, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Housing Advocates, 1983-1984 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Housing Conservation Coordinators, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Housing Fund New York City Housing Fund, 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Housing Homeless Families, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Housing in New York: The Challenge and the Opportunity -- Report to New York City Council President, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Housing Initiative Fund, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Housing Justice Campaign, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Housing Justice Campaign 1987, 1985-1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Housing New York State Elderly Population, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Housing Policy, 1975-1994 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Housing Policy -- Single Room Occupancy Appeal Case Against City of New York, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Housing Policy Local and National Issues, 1984-2003 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Housing Preservation and Development -- Gliedman to Ron Letter Regarding 1985 Housing Vacancy Survey, 1985-1987 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Housing Preservation and Development Miscellaneous Documents 1996-2002, 1984-2002 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Housing Reducing Housing Costs and Brownfields, 1994-2000 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Housing Seminar -- Rosenbloom, 1985-1986 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Housing Works Newsletter, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Housing, Liberty Bonds, Land Use, 2001-2003 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - The Impact of Washington Reforms on New York City, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Insurance Redlining, Fact not Fiction -- Adivsory committees to US Commission on Civil Rights, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Land Use and Housing, A Redistributive Model, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Low-Income Housing Crisis: Can Solutions be Found?, 1988 (Box 140, Item 347)
      Audiocasette.
    - Low Income Home Improvement Program, 1980-1983 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Low Income Housing Coalition, 1980-1984 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Mental Health Law Project, 1982-1990 (Box 24, Folder 7-12)
    - Neighborhood Home Improvement Loan Program, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Neighborhood Strategy Areas Testimony -- Brian Sullivan and Ron Shiffman, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - New York City Housing and Community Development Coalition, 1980-1983 (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
    - New York City Housing Authority, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - New York City Housing Partnership, 1985-1992 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - New York City's Community Development Corporation Issues, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - New York Housing Authority, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - New York Housing Conference, 1995-1997 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - New York State Assembly Affordable Housing Unit, 2009 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Office of Mental Health, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Pacific House -- Technical Assistance, 1985-1991 (Box 25, Folder 12-13)
    - Performance Zoning for Sustainable Development, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Perspecta 31 Roundtable Discussion, 1994-1996 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Peter C. Goldmark, Jr. Regional Plan Association, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - PICCED Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Planning Democracy and Reason, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - The Politics of Budget Decisions in Communities and Bronx Housing, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Proposed Housing Models -- AIDS Housing Coalition Reports, 1987-1989 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Public and Private Sector + Community = Housing, Center for Architecture, August 4, 2005 (Box 142, Item 416)
    - Public and Private Sector + Community = Housing, Center for Architecture, 2005 (Box 142, Item 417)
    - Public and Private Sector + Community = Housing, Center for Architecture, 2005 (Box 142, Item 418)
    - Public/Private Ventures' States of Change Report on Work-First Policy, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Red Hook Revitalization and Green Neighborhoods, 1994-2005 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Regional Plan Association, 1997-2002 (Box 62, Folder 1-4)
    - Regional Plan Association, 1991 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Regional Plan Association, 2000-2003 (Box 62, Folder 6-7)
    - Regional Plan Association, 1991 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Regional Plan Association -- Smart Growth Regional Plan Association, 1999 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Regional Plan Association and New Amsterdam Development Consultants, Inc., 2003 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Renigades Renigades Housing Movement, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Rent Regulation Control, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Rental Housing Assistance, 1997-1999 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Ron New York City Mayor's Commercial Rent Control Task Force, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Ron Recommendations, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Same Boat Coalition City-Wide Strategic Discussion, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Schur Robert Schur, 1975-1981 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Single Room Occupancy Law Clippings, circa 1980-1990 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Squatters Clippings, 1987-1994 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - State Commission on Housing, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 9-10)
    - Strycker's Bay Proposals, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Tax Reform Act of 1986 -- Low-Income Housing Tax Credits and Other Provisions (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Testimonial of 3/24/81, 1981-1982 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Testimony -- June 1984 New York City Board of Estimate (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Testimony September 22, 1983 Inclusionary Zoning -- Brian P. Davidoff and Ron P. Tegler (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Toward an Economic and Social Accounting System for Bedford-Stuyvesant, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Toward an Economic and Social Accounting System for Bedford-Stuyvesant, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Uniform Land Use Review Procedure (ULURP), 1990-2000 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - University Consortium for Neighborhood Research and Development, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - University of Illinois at Chicago Affordable Housing Design Catalogue, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - West Side Community Alliance Alternative to Welfare Proposal to Acuire and Renovate Properties, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Westside SRO Law Project, 1985-1989 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Sub-series 2.2: Mutual Housing and Land Trusts
    - 100 West 88th St, Strycker's Bay, 1988-1990 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - 103, 05, 07, 09, West 88th St, Strycker's Bay, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - 108 West 95th St, Strycker's Bay, 1986-1990 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - 133-135 West 89th St, Strycker's Bay, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - 1992 In rem stock/Community Assisted Tenant Controlled Housing/Community Housing Association of Managers and Producers/Community Service Society Study/CMP/NOW (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - 7 West 92 St Strycker's Bay, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - 72 West 88th St Strycker's Bay, 1988-1990 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - ACORN, 1985-1987 (Box 27, Folder 18-19)
    - Articles -- Background NYC and Self Help Housing, 1991-1994 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Chemical Bank, 1988-1989 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Chemical Community Development, Inc., 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Cooper Square, 1990-1993 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Cooper Square 5/91, 1986-1991 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Cooper Square Committee -- Background Reports, 1986-1990 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Cooper Square Interim/Phasing, 1986-1991 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - David Dinkins Mutual Housing Trust, 1989-1993 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Developing Housing Trust Funds, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Gottlieb 5189 Building Monitering, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Heinz Neighborhood Development Program Grant United Tenants Association Mutual Housing Association, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - HUPC Mutual Housing Associaton of New York, 1987-1990 (Box 28, Folder 10-11)
    - Inclusionary Zoning and Housing Trust Fund, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - LEVITT Proposal, 1991-1993 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - LEVITT Proposal -- Notes, Outline, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Mary Brooks Housing Trust Fund, 1982-1989 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Midwood Friends 1994 Tax Returns, 1994-1995 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Midwood Friends 1995 Tax Returns, 1995-1996 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Midwood Friends 1996 Tax Returns, 1997-1998 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Midwood Friends 1997 Tax Returns, 1997-1998 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Midwood Friends 1998 Tax Returns (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Midwood Friends 1999 Tax Returns, 1998-1999 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Midwood Friends 2000 Tax Returns, 2000-2001 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Midwood Friends 2001 Tax Returns, 2001-2002 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Midwood Friends 2002 Tax Returns, 2002-2003 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Midwood Friends 2003 Tax Returns, 2003-2004 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Midwood Friends 2004 Tax Returns, 2004-2005 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Midwood Friends 2006 Tax Returns, 2006-2007 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Midwood Friends 2007 Tax Returns, 2007-2008 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Midwood Friends 2008 Tax Returns, 2008-2009 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Midwood Friends Bank Statements, 2007-2010 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Midwood Friends DC Checks 1991 and Bank Statements, 1990-1991 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Midwood Friends Development Corporation, 1987-1992 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Midwood Friends Development Corporation 1993-1994 Tax Returns (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Midwood Friends Development Corporation Bank Statements, 1993-1994 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Midwood Friends Invoices, 2002 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Midwood Friends Money Market Bank Statements, 1990-2001 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Association Correspondence with Attorney From April 1993, 1993-2008 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust 1993 Bank Statement (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust 1993-1994 Tax Returns, 1993-1997 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust Account -- Checking, 1992-1995 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust Account -- Money Market, 1993-1998 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust Agreement, 1990-2010 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust Correspondence with Accountants, 1992-2010 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust Dime Savings Bank, 1990-1993 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust Disbursement -- Juan Perez Distribution, 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust Financial, 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust Money Market Account Bank Statements, 2002-2006 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Midwood Friends Tenants Trust Sofia Benitez, Sol Stoll Disbursement, 1991-2003 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Midwood Friends Trust Mida Miranda Distribution, 2003 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Midwood Garden Projections, 1991-2009 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Midwood Garden Projections, 1991-2009 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Midwood Gardens, 1988-1990 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Midwood Gardens, 1986-1992 (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
    - Midwood Gardens, Margarent Criscola Midwood Friends Trust Distribution, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Migda Midwood Friends Trust Soto Distribution, 2003 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Mutual Housing Association Case Studies, 1987-1993 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Mutual Housing Association of New York, undated (Box 143, Item 391)
    - Mutual Housing Association of New York, 1983-1997 (Box 32, Folder 7-12)
    - Mutual Housing Associaton of New York -- Board Meetings, 1990-1992 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Mutual Housing Association-MD / Mental Health Law Project, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - New York City Coalition for a Fair Federal Budget, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - New York Hispanic Housing Coalition Pratt Membership Certificate, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - People's Mutual Housing Association, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - PICCED UTA Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Piedmont Housing Alliance, undated (Box 142, Item 442)
    - Ron's Testimony -- Housing Trust Fund, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Strycker's, 1982-1991 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
    - Strycker's Bay -- Phase II, Commercial Space Design, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Strycker's Bay Neighborhood Council -- Draft of Scope of Services, 1986-1987 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Strycker's Bay YCK, 1986-1988 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Strycker's Current Scopes, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Testimony Housing Trust Fund -- Board of Estimate, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - United Tenants Association Building Operation Data Current, 1989-1990 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - United Tenants Association Heinz Neighborhood Development Program, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - United Tenants Association Meetings Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - United Tenants Association Mutual Housing Association -- Includes Stryker's Bay, 1989-1992 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - United Tenants Association Mutual Housing Association Development, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - United Tenants Association Mutual Housing Association Operations, 1986-1993 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - United Tenants Association Scopes, 1986-1990 (Box 34, Folder 5)
- Series 3: Community Development
  This series includes materials about community development in Brooklyn and New York City. The first sub-series contains general research, proposals and reports about Brooklyn neighborhoods such as Bedford-Stuyvesant, the waterfront, Crown Heights, and Greenpoint. The Essex Street Market, Cooper Square and other city-wide locations are also represented. Topics addressed in these materials include Business Improvement Districts, manufacturing, small business retail, day care provision, human rights, and the establishment of the Benjamin Banneker Academy for Community Development, a New Visions high school operated by the NYC Department of Education.
  The second sub-series includes project files from specific community development initiatives, for which Shiffman and the Pratt Center provided support. The majority of materials pertain to the Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation. The sub-series also includes information on the Association of Neighborhood Housing Developers, and the Urban Homesteading Assistance Board, as well as the re-building of New Orleans after hurricane Katrina.
  The third sub-series contains the project files for Building Hope: The Community Development Corporation Oral History Project. Funded by the Ford Foundation, this project conducted interviews with leaders from nineteen Community Development Corporations across the country. In addition to project planning, financial, and outreach materials, this sub-series includes transcripts from many of the interviews conducted during this project. There is also a small amount of materials pertaining to the history of the Pratt Center. The final sub-series contains audio-visual recordings from the Building Hope oral history project.
  Material in this series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Sub-series 3.1: Research and Reports
    - 840 Second Concourse, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - A Case Against Tall Buildings, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - A Human Rights Impact Statement for New York State, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - A Workshop on Community Based Economic Development, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - ABCDesign Conference, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - AFL-CIO, 1984-1985 (Box 35, Folder 4)